Sofia Eriksen

Curiculum Vitae

Georg-Schwarz-Strasse 50 04177 Leipzig, Germany ⑤ (+49) 178 3670115 ⋈ sofia.eriksen@gmail.com

Sofia Eriksen is currently pursuing a Ph.D. at the Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology in the department of Human Behaviour, Ecology, and Culture led by Prof. Dr. Richard McElreath, conducting fieldwork in Ulukhaktok, Canada. Sofia is interested in the application of social psychological theory to improve the efficacy of policies and interventions, particularly within the intersection of social identities, cultural change, and well-being. Sofia grew up abroad, living in Latvia, Bosnia-Herzegovina, Azerbaijan, Ukraine, and Syria before completing an International Baccalaureate in Denmark. Sofia pursued her higher education in Scotland, where she gained experience in report writing, literature reviews, analyses with R, applied psychometrics, quantitative-and qualitative methods, and research in line with Open Science and FAIR principles. Sofia completed her undergraduate degree in Psychology with first class honours at the University of Stirling and her postgraduate degree in Social Psychology with distinction at the University of Edinburgh.

Education

2024 Ph.D., Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology, Department of Human Behaviour, Ecology, and Culture.

Supervised by Dr. Elspeth Ready.

2022–2023 M.Sc., Social Psychology, University of Edinburgh, with Distinction.

2018–2022 **B.Sc.**, Psychology, University of Stirling, with First Class Honours.

2015–2017 International Baccalaureate, Aarhus Gymnasium, 36 points.

Research Experience

- 2023 **M.Sc. Thesis**, Exploring message framing effects on EDI (equality, diversity, inclusivity) initiative support: Social identity threat as a mediator.

 Supervised by Dr. Helena Radke and Dr. Lyndsey Wallace, University of Edinburgh
- 2022 B.Sc. Thesis, Investigating the relationship between COVID-19 vaccination and seasonal influenza vaccination uptake.
 Supervised by Dr. Pamela Rackow, University of Stirling
- 2021–2022 Work Placement, Dementia Friendly Dunblane (DFD).

As part of my B.Sc., I completed a work placement at a local third sector organisation. I assisted DFD during their transition to a meeting centre for vulnerable elderly people, in line with research conducted by Dröes et al. (2003). I completed a comprehensive literature review, assisted with grant applications, and participated in steering committee meetings. I also designed and distributed surveys to DFD members, with the aim of identifying potential shortcomings during the transitional period as well as evaluating general well-being. The surveys were supported by findings from informal conversations, as many members preferred these. Lastly, I was also a befriender, meaning I regularly met with a member with dementia in my personal time. My placement culminated in an essay, with the findings presented at the University of Stirling's final-year Psychology Conference.

Volunteering

2022–2023 Editor, Edinburgh University Psychology Magazine (EUPM).

I edited online blog posts and journal articles written by students. The latter contributed to the annual issue of the University of Edinburgh's psychology magazine. The topic for 2023 was "The Rich Man's World," with emphasis placed on gender and economic inequalities in the UK.

2022 **Befriender**, Dementia Friendly Dunblane (DFD).

After completing my work placement, I stayed on as a befriender and volunteer.

2016–2018 **Volunteer**, DanChurchSocial (Kirkens Korshær), Aarhus.

I organised thrift stores and collected donations to help the "weakest" in our society. I gained experience in forming new relations, offering support, and working with people from all backgrounds.

2014–2016 Instructor, Aarhus Pistol Klub, Aarhus.

In collaboration with the club, I led introductory training sessions for new shooters, presenting the relevant safety material and supervising conduct on the range. Additionally, I participated in weekly sessions with smaller groups of children diagnosed with ADHD.

Awards

2022 Nordea Fonden.

€1350 awarded for academic excellence to fund M.Sc.

2022 Augustinus Fonden.

€4700 awarded for academic excellence to fund M.Sc.

2022 William Demant Fonden.

€2700 awarded for academic excellence to fund M.Sc.

2022 Knud Højgaards Fonden.

€2000 awarded for academic excellence to fund M.Sc.

Skills

Software R, R Markdown, XLSForm, LaTeX, Microsoft Office

Languages English (native), Danish (native)